<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Challenge on The Wizard&#39;s Manse</title>
    <link>http://thewizardsmanse.com/categories/challenge/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Challenge on The Wizard&#39;s Manse</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2017 The Wizard&#39;s Manse.</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://thewizardsmanse.com/categories/challenge/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Fun with HDTV Antennas</title>
      <link>http://thewizardsmanse.com/fun-with-hdtv-antennas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 00:53:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thewizardsmanse.com/fun-with-hdtv-antennas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My cable internet provider recently switched to all digital channels so that they could encrypt local broadcasts. This put me in a bit of a bind since all my TVs were using built-in QAM tuners to get local stations. I needed to supply signals to three TVs and two &lt;a href=&#34;http://smile.amazon.com/Hauppauge-1213-WinTV-HVR-2255-Control-Receiver/dp/B001E2V7R8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;HDTV capture cards&lt;/a&gt; on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Home_theater_PC&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;HTPC&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My options were, pay $3/month/tv to the cable company for digital boxes to get &amp;#8220;free&amp;#8221; OTA (over the air) broadcasts or pay $70 for a &lt;a href=&#34;http://smile.amazon.com/gp/product/B00CXQO00K?psc=1&amp;redirect=true&amp;ref_=ox_sc_sfl_title_1&amp;smid=ATVPDKIKX0DER&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;high-end HDTV antenna&lt;/a&gt; plus an &lt;a href=&#34;http://smile.amazon.com/DuaFire-Antenna-Amplifier-Booster-Supply-up/dp/B0196AN9WU/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1453048463&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=antenna+amplifier&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;amplifier&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://smile.amazon.com/BAMF-4-Way-Splitter-Bi-Directional-5-2300MHz/dp/B017T9KF1S/ref=sr_1_1?s=electronics&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1453049025&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=4+way+catv+splitter&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;splitter&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://smile.amazon.com/dp/B001222256?psc=1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;amplified splitter&lt;/a&gt; and rewire my house to hook the antenna up to all my TVs while still allowing my cable internet to get to my cable modem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neither option seemed appealing to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I stumbled upon a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.instructables.com/id/Powerful-Modern-Homemade-HDTV-Antenna/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;homemade HDTV antenna&lt;/a&gt; project that looked very interesting. It had a link to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://hubpages.com/art/make-this-powerful-hdtv-antenna-out-of-cardboard&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;original PDF template&lt;/a&gt; that you can print out on legal paper. The project was simple enough that I decided to give it a go. I already had cardboard, aluminum foil, model/craft glue, a box cutter, an exacto knife, and a printer. I used to have a balun lying around, but it got thrown out during spring cleaning a few years back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The antenna took about 2 hours to build. It is important to follow the template exactly because the size is very important to receive HDTV signals. After spending all evening building a single antenna I still had to get a &lt;a href=&#34;http://smile.amazon.com/300-Ohm-UHF-Matching-Transformer/dp/B0002ZPIOG/ref=sr_1_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1453561976&amp;amp;sr=8-2&amp;amp;keywords=balun&#34;&gt;balun&lt;/a&gt;. Here&amp;#8217;s the result:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_155&#34; style=&#34;width: 190px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption alignleft&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://thewizardsmanse.com/2016/01/Antenna_1.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;attachment wp-att-155&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;wp-image-155 size-full&#34; src=&#34;http://thewizardsmanse.com/2016/01/Antenna_1.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Double Bowtie Antenna&#34; width=&#34;180&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    Double Bowtie Antenna
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_156&#34; style=&#34;width: 190px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption alignleft&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://thewizardsmanse.com/2016/01/Antenna_2.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;attachment wp-att-156&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;wp-image-156 size-full&#34; src=&#34;http://thewizardsmanse.com/2016/01/Antenna_2.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Double Bowtie Reflector&#34; width=&#34;180&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    Double Bowtie Reflector
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tvfool.com/&#34;&gt;tvfool.com&lt;/a&gt; I should be able to get three UHF channels (NBC, ABC, and CBS) and one VHF channel (PBS). Fox and CW are broadcast as virtual channels on two of the UHF channels, so they don&amp;#8217;t show up on tvfool. The double bowtie antenna is able to pick up all three UHF channels but not the VHF channel. I had to place it about 4 feet off the ground and angle it to pick up one of the channels. Another channel is powerful enough to pick it up even though it is located behind the reflector. I connected the antenna to a 4-way spitter that feeds my two capture cards and one of my TVs. The splitter isn&amp;#8217;t powered or amplified, so the output is 25% of the input, but the signal from the antenna is still powerful enough to feed all three channels to all three consumers clearly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s an impressive antenna!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I returned to the instructables site to see if there were any easier antenna builds. I stumbled on this comment:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;comment-header&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;comment-author&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;author-link pro&#34; href=&#34;http://www.instructables.com/member/NotTheDude&#34;&gt;NotTheDude&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;action btn btn-mini pull-right replyToCommentBtn login-required&#34;&gt;Reply&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;comment-date pull-right comment-info&#34;&gt;3 years ago&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;comment-body-container&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;comment-body&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      It may not look as cool as this or other homemade HDTV antennas, but you can save yourself the cost of buying anything new and the work it takes to put one of these things together by simply taking a spare coaxial cable and cutting about 8 inches of insulation off the end so you have the center wire exposed. Then move it around until you get the best reception. You will not believe it until you try it, but this works better than any other antenna I have ever used for over-the-air digital TV.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      I have tried every antenna possible from dollar store 10 buck antennas to $50 Phillips HDTV indoor/outdoor antenna and the bare wire works better than them all (even when I put the $50 antenna on my roof). I have removed the insulation from about a dozen or so coaxial cables for friends and families over the past 4 years and they are all still using them because they work better than anything else.they have bought themselves.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      I would make an indestructible for this, but it&amp;#8217;s so easy I couldn&amp;#8217;t explain it any better except to take a picture of it. I will say that it can be hard to slide the entire 8 inches of insulation off the end all at once so just cut an inch or two of the insulation at a time and it comes off pretty easily.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      Try it and you will be surprised how well it works. What do you have to lose?
    &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;comment-body&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Wow&lt;/strong&gt;! That is a &lt;strong&gt;lot&lt;/strong&gt; easier than a two hour build. I gave that a shot on the TV in my bathroom.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;comment-body&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div id=&#34;attachment_157&#34; style=&#34;width: 190px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption alignleft&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://thewizardsmanse.com/2016/01/Antenna_3.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;attachment wp-att-157&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;wp-image-157 size-full&#34; src=&#34;http://thewizardsmanse.com/2016/01/Antenna_3.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Whip Antenna&#34; width=&#34;180&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
      Whip Antenna
    &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was only able to pick up one channel with two stations, but it was the one channel that I want to watch in the mornings when I&amp;#8217;m getting ready for work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out there is a name for this type of antenna; NotTheDude was describing a whip antenna.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s where my post becomes really technical. I&amp;#8217;ll skip over most of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.antenna-theory.com/basics/frequency.php&#34;&gt;physics&lt;/a&gt;, but you need to understand that each channel is a different frequency that is unrelated to the &amp;#8220;virtual channel&amp;#8221; that is displayed on your TV. You also need to understand that the length of the &amp;#8220;whip&amp;#8221; is directly related to the channel that it can receive. A whip antenna doesn&amp;#8217;t amplify the the signal it receives but the coax cable will lose signal strength over long runs (4-6dB over 100 feet), so you want to keep the cable as short as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tvfool.com lets you enter your address and it will show the channels you can receive. It also shows the signal strength for each channel at your location. If you enter the height of the antenna above ground, then the signal indication will be more accurate. The channels I wanted to receive were all rated at 50dB or higher and to receive the channel it needs to be greater than 0dB once you account for signal gains and loss by your antenna, coax, splitters, and amplifiers. Using NotTheDude&amp;#8217;s advice I cut the whip to 8&amp;#8243;, which as it turns out is perfect for receiving the upper end of UHF. The channel I wanted to receive was #50, which is the upper end of the UHF frequencies. I tested another whip of 12&amp;#8243; and was able to receive a channel at the lower end, but not both. The third channel I could not receive no matter the length.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still couldn&amp;#8217;t receive the VHF channel. I did some more research, and you can calculate the exact length of the whip for the channel you want to receive. You need to look up the physical channel number (not the virtual ##.# channel the TV displays) to get &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/North_American_television_frequencies#UHF_band&#34;&gt;the frequency&lt;/a&gt;. You then enter the frequency in this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.csgnetwork.com/antennagenericfreqlencalc.html&#34;&gt;calculator&lt;/a&gt; to get the whip length for the half wavelength. The whip length for UHF ranges from around 12&amp;#8243; for the lower frequencies to around 8&amp;#8243; for the higher frequencies. If I wanted to pick up the VHF channel to get PBS, then according to that calculator, I would need a whip length of 30&amp;#8243;&amp;#8230; um, no thanks. That means I&amp;#8217;d need a signal combiner that won&amp;#8217;t cause interference between the two whips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried a 12&amp;#8243; whip antenna on my upstairs TV and found that I was able to pick up all three UHF stations. That was much easier than building another double bowtie antenna! The one channel on the higher frequency was powerful enough to force its way onto the longer antenna.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So&amp;#8230; if a 12&amp;#8243; whip can pick up all three UHF stations on the second floor (around 25&amp;#8242; &amp;#8211; 30&amp;#8242; above ground level), then maybe I could move the whip in my bathroom up to the attic to pick them all up. The problem might be dB loss in the 30&amp;#8242; of coax. I found a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w4rp.com/ref/coax.html&#34;&gt;table that shows dB loss in coax&lt;/a&gt;. It shows for RG-6 (standard tv cable) between 4dB and 6dB loss for 100&amp;#8242; depending on the channel frequency. That means I should expect between 1dB to 2dB loss. Tvfool.com showed that I should have plenty of signal strength, so up to the attic I went. I spliced into the existing cable and used a &lt;a href=&#34;http://smile.amazon.com/Splice-F-81-Adapter-DC-3GHz/dp/B008R3J4QS/ref=sr_1_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1453077536&amp;amp;sr=8-2&amp;amp;keywords=rg-6+coupler&#34;&gt;coupler&lt;/a&gt; to install a 12&amp;#8243; whip at about 30&amp;#8242; above ground level with about 30&amp;#8242; of coax cable connecting it to the TV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The setup worked perfectly and I can now receive CBS, ABC, NBC, FOX, and CW on all my TVs and capture cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;comment-body&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple App Accounts Using BlueStacks</title>
      <link>http://thewizardsmanse.com/multiple-app-accounts-using-bluestacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2013 17:43:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thewizardsmanse.com/multiple-app-accounts-using-bluestacks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When you use apps on a device such as an iPhone or Android phone, you may run into a situation where you want to have multiple accounts for the same app. Unfortunately, this can be very hard to do. It usually requires you to uninstall the app and re-install it to switch accounts. Usually these apps don&amp;#8217;t have a PC version, which makes it even harder to manage multiple accounts. The people at BlueStacks have written an Android emulator to allow running apps on a PC (they have a MAC version, but it doesn&amp;#8217;t support the version of Android required to run most apps), so you will need Windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To run multiple accounts of an app follow these steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download and install &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bluestacks.com/&#34;&gt;BlueStacks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install the app that you want to duplicate, but do not log in or create an account. If you have already logged into the app, then uninstall the app and re-install it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open Windows Explorer and go to %ProgramData%\BlueStacks\Android\ you should see a folder called Data.sparsefs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rename Data.sparsefs to Data1.sparsefs.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make as many copies of Data1.sparsefs as you need copies of your app. Increment the number after Data each time. You should end up with something like this, but without the Data.sparsefs folder.
&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_109&#34; style=&#34;width: 242px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://thewizardsmanse.com/2013/12/Data.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-109&#34; alt=&#34;data folders&#34; src=&#34;http://thewizardsmanse.com/2013/12/Data.jpg&#34; width=&#34;232&#34; height=&#34;214&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    copies of data folders
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://thewizardsmanse.com/2013/12/LaunchApp.zip&#34;&gt;Download this zip file&lt;/a&gt;, open it, and copy LaunchApp.bat to %ProgramData%\BlueStacks\Android&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the apps folder that BlueStacks installed on your desktop. You should see a shortcut to the app that you installed in BlueStacks.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Right-click on the shortcut and choose &amp;#8220;properties&amp;#8221;. You should see a window like this:
&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_111&#34; style=&#34;width: 495px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://thewizardsmanse.com/2013/12/Properties.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-111&#34; alt=&#34;link properties&#34; src=&#34;http://thewizardsmanse.com/2013/12/Properties.jpg&#34; width=&#34;485&#34; height=&#34;611&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    link properties
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#8217;ll need to edit the text inside the &amp;#8220;Target&amp;#8221; textbox. you want to keep the last two arguments. Those will tell BlueStacks which app you want to launch. If you were editing the twitter link, then&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;C:\Program Files (x86)\BlueStacks\HD-RunApp.exe&amp;#8221; Android com.twitter.android com.twitter.android.StartActivity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;becomes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;%ProgramData%\BlueStacks\Android\LaunchApp.bat 1 com.twitter.android com.twitter.android.StartActivity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice that the &amp;#8220;Android&amp;#8221; became a &amp;#8220;1&amp;#8221;. That &amp;#8220;1&amp;#8221; will change for each shortcut to match the Data#.sparsefs that you want to link to.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a copy of the shortcut for each copy of Data.sparsefs that you created&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rename each link with the number that corresponds to the number in your copy of Data.sparsefs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edit the target of each link, just like in step 8. Change the &amp;#8220;1&amp;#8221; to match the number in your copy of Data.sparsefs&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should end up with links like these:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_110&#34; style=&#34;width: 376px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://thewizardsmanse.com/2013/12/Apps.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-110&#34; alt=&#34;app links&#34; src=&#34;http://thewizardsmanse.com/2013/12/Apps.jpg&#34; width=&#34;366&#34; height=&#34;470&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
              
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    links to apps
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
            

&lt;p&gt;Now, when you double-click the links, the batch file will link the proper Data#.sparsefs and launch your app. The first time you run each shortcut you will need to set up a new account. After that, you can switch accounts just by launching the shortcut.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image Processing Part 1</title>
      <link>http://thewizardsmanse.com/image-processing-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2012 04:16:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thewizardsmanse.com/image-processing-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is, hopefully, the first in a series of posts using this codebase. The topics will be varied, but hopefully the codebase will tie them together&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can you tell what is different between this image:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://thewizardsmanse.com/2012/11/Redbud.JPG&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-30 aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;Redbud&#34; src=&#34;http://thewizardsmanse.com/2012/11/Redbud.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Origional Redbud image&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and this one:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://thewizardsmanse.com/2012/11/Redbud2.bmp&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-31&#34; title=&#34;Redbud2&#34; src=&#34;http://thewizardsmanse.com/2012/11/Redbud2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Modified Redbud Image&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from the obvious visual differences, there is an important, hidden difference. You can click-through and grab the original versions and try to figure it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer is below&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was reading a story in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.asimovs.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Asimovs&lt;/a&gt; a while back (for the life of me, I cannot rember the name or month) where the charactors encoded messages by manipulating the pixels of an image. I thought that was an interesting idea, and decided to try it as a proof of concept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created a project that opens an image, encodes some text into the image, and saves the result. It can also open the resulting image, decode the text, and display it. Notice that I said it &lt;strong&gt;encodes&lt;/strong&gt; the text and not &lt;strong&gt;encrypts&lt;/strong&gt; there is a big difference, and that will be handled later. By merely encoding the text, anyone who knows the algorithm can decode and read the text. The text encoded in the image is no different from text encoded as ASCII or Unicode. It is just an electronic representation of text. The idea here is to use &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Security_through_obscurity&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;security through obscurity&lt;/a&gt;. Anyone seeing the output image by itself should find no obvious signs of an encoded message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I grabbed a copy of _&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/12&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Through the Looking Glass&lt;/a&gt;_ from Project Gutenberg and encoded it into the image above. I accomplish this by manipulating the green value of each pixel. Perhaps for this image it would be better to use the blue value&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s a look at the code:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I need to assign a numeric value to the text that I wish to encode. I use an ASCII encoded to convert the text to a byte array:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class=&#34;brush: csharp; title: ; notranslate&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;public static void Encode(Bitmap image, string text, int pixelsPerByte) 
{
  var bytes = new ASCIIEncoding().GetBytes(text);
  Encode(image, bytes, pixelsPerByte); 
}
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because C# uses one byte for each channel of a pixel (red, green, blue, and alpha) and one byte for each character in ASCII text we could simply encode the text directly as an image. This, of course, would nullify our security through obscurity because it wouldn&amp;#8217;t appear to be a real image. Through experimentation, I found that manipulating only one channel to be best. I also don&amp;#8217;t want to completely overwrite an entire channel with a full byte of text, so I split each character across multiple pixels:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class=&#34;brush: csharp; title: ; notranslate&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;public static void Encode(Bitmap image, byte[] bytes, int pixelsPerByte) 
{
  var totalBytes = image.Height*image.Width/pixelsPerByte;
  if(totalBytes &amp;lt; bytes.Length)
    throw new ApplicationException(&#34;Image too small to encode text.&#34;);
 
  var byteList = bytes.ToList();
  byteList.AddRange(Enumerable.Repeat((byte)0, totalBytes - bytes.Length));
  byteList.Add(0);
 
  for (var c = 0; c &amp;lt; byteList.Count; c++)
  {
    if (ComputePixel(image, byteList, c, pixelsPerByte))
      break;
  }
}
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, through experimentation, I found that 32 pixels per caracter works well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My method for encoding the data is to average the red and blue channels together and assign that value to the green channel. I then take my partial byte of text and either add it to or subtract it from the green channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class=&#34;brush: csharp; title: ; notranslate&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;private static bool ComputePixel(Bitmap image, IReadOnlyList&amp;lt;byte&amp;gt; bytes, int c, int pixelsPerByte)
{
  var b = bytes;
  var partial = b/pixelsPerByte;
  var last = b - (partial*(pixelsPerByte-1));
  var partialBytes = Enumerable.Repeat(partial, pixelsPerByte - 1).ToList();
  partialBytes.Add(last);
  for (var i = 0; i &amp;lt; pixelsPerByte; i++)
  {
    var x = ((c * pixelsPerByte) + i) % image.Width;
    var y = ((c * pixelsPerByte) + i) / image.Width;
    if (y &amp;lt;= image.Height) 
      return true; 
    var color = image.GetPixel(x, y);
    var green = (color.R + color.B)/2;
    
    if (green &amp;gt;= 128)
      green -= partialBytes[i];
    else
      green += partialBytes[i];
    
    color = Color.FromArgb(color.A, color.R, green, color.B);
    image.SetPixel(x, y, color);
  }
  return false; 
}
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This algorithm is reversible, which is very handy if you want to decode the text&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may have noticed that the modified image was rather large. That is because we must save the image in a way that doesn&amp;#8217;t modify the bits. .net makes saving the image easy, but using any of the other format will destroy the encoded text when the image is compressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class=&#34;brush: csharp; title: ; notranslate&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;private void SaveToolStripMenuItemClick(object sender, EventArgs e)
{
  if (saveFileDialog1.ShowDialog() == DialogResult.OK)
    ((EncoderModel) encoderModelBindingSource.Current).Image.Save(saveFileDialog1.FileName, ImageFormat.MemoryBmp);
}
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenge to you is to create another algorithm that produces a better looking image, while still remaining reversible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can download the code from the main branch of my gitHub repository: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nathanrobinson/ImageTextEncoder&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;nathanrobinson/ImageTextEncoder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then alter ComputePixel and ComputeByte to encode and decode the text. Some ideas would be to use Hue, Saturation, and Value, instead of Red, Green, and Blue; convert the image from color to grayscale; or something completely different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me know what cool ideas you come up with.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>